LAMONT THOMPSON

+18483134428 | mont3@thompson-techconsulting.com | linkedin.com/in/lamont-thompson-profile/ github.com/lthompson1206 | thompson-techconsulting.com/

SUMMARY

Cloud Support Engineer with a strong background in web development, API Development, and technical support. Offering expertise in AWS Cloud Services and a commitment to optimizing infrastructure for scalability, reliability, and security. I also have a high aptitude for DevOps principles.

EDUCATION

South University

September 2012 - December 2014

GPA:3

Bachelor's, Information Science

- Introduction to Information Technology
- **Database Management Systems**
- Networking and Data Communications
- Cybersecurity Fundamentals
- **Cloud Computing**
- IT Infrastructure and Hardware

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Practitioner

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Greenthumbup Remote

Cloud Application Developer

January 2020 - Present

- Led the creation of three websites for Greenthumbup Ministries. Leveraged cutting-edge cloud solutions and innovative serverless architectures.
- Collaborated within a dynamic team, synergizing technical skills to streamline the development process.
- Utilized AWS and A.I. to expedite project completion by 30%, emphasizing cloud solutions and security measures.
- Contributed to the accelerated success and growth of Greenthumbup Ministries in the digital landscape in the Cannabis & Agricultural industries

Thompson-Tech Consulting

Remote

Web Developer

October 2017 - Present Orchestrated the development of visually captivating and user-friendly websites for three small businesses as the Lead

- Web Developer at Thompson-Tech Consulting.
- Translated design concepts into interactive and responsive web interfaces, employing HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React frameworks to enhance the user experience.
- Managed the entire project life cycle, showcasing proficiency as both a skilled Web Developer and an efficient Technical Project Manager in the dual responsibility role.

Altice (Optimum) Newark, NJ, USA

Technical Support

- Delivering exceptional customer service for their IoT products and services
- I leveraged strong communication skills to guide customers through problem-solving steps, address inquiries, and maintain a high level of customer satisfaction
- This position involves diagnosing and resolving technical issues, coordinating with other support teams as needed, and staying updated on the latest technology to provide accurate and efficient solutions.

PROJECTS & OUTSIDE EXPERIENCE

Trapnerdsolutions Remote

Web Developer

January 2021 - June 2021

March 2015 - October 2017

A Lead Web Developer utilizing React framework and wordpress backend technologies to create web application. You can find it on portfolio website at Thompson-TechConsulting.com

SKILLS

Skills: Adobe Illustrator, Git, HTML/CSS, Python, Excel/Numbers/Sheets, SEO, Infrastructure as Code, CI/CD, AWS Lambda, Kubernetes, Cloud Security, Networking Principles, JavaScript, JIRA, CloudFormation, Agile, SCRUM, Cloud Infrastructure, DevOps, Automation, Docker, Scripting (e.g., Python), Serverless Computing, AWS Lambda, Database Management, Networking, Wordpress, Artificial Intelligence